Good Morning, Church!
You may be seated. Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, give me your heart.
We are overwhelmed by many things.
We are overwhelmed by many distractions.
Jesus needs your heart.
That is a place of contact.
Tell your neighbour.
Jesus needs your heart.
That is a place of what? - Contact.
Oh Holy Spirit, free our heart to follow You.
I can't hear you.
Oh Holy Spirit, free my spirit to follow You.
The message is going to terminate every spiritual weakness.
It's going to be terminated today.
Every spiritual weakness in you will be terminated.
It's a prayer language.
While I'm talking to you, while you're looking at me and I'm looking at you,
keep saying in your spirit, "Oh Holy Spirit, free my spirit to follow You".
Many spirits are in bondage - bondage of unforgiveness,
bondage of anger, bondage of hatred, bondage of bitterness - just name it.
Bondage.
To all the hearts that are in bondage - listen:"Oh Holy Spirit, free my spirit to follow You".
Are you busy with that?
You can be saying it repeatedly until it becomes a reality to you.
Come on!
That is the easiest way to invite Jesus into your heart.
Free my spirit to follow You.
I have decided to follow Jesus
No turning back
I would want to take you to the book of 2 Peter.
Whilst you are opening 2 Peter, that should not stop you from your meditation.
Your meditation should continue.
Are you there?
2 Peter 1.
We take our reading from verse 1.
"Simon Peter, a servant and apostle of Jesus Christ,
to those who through the righteousness of our God and Saviour Jesus Christ
have received a faith as precious as ours:"
Verse 2.
"Grace and peace be yours in abundance through the knowledge of God
and of our Lord Jesus Christ."
Verse 3.
"...His divine power has given us everything we need for a godly life through our knowledge
of Him who called us by His own glory and goodness."
Let's go to our proof text.
Verse 20.
"Above all, you must understand that no prophecy of scripture came about
by the prophet's own interpretation of things."
Verse 21.
"For prophecy never had its origin in the human will, but prophets, though human..."
Listen to that - "prophets, though human".
T.B. Joshua is human.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is divine.
Take note of that.
Everyone has two natures in one person.
"...prophets, though human, spoke from God as they were carried along by the Holy Spirit."
I want to take you up today on our standard for life.
As Christians, this is our standard for life.
This is my standard for life.
This is your standard for life.
So, because the way we go about the Bible,
we don't know the difference between the Bible and other books,
the difference between the Bible and history,
the difference between the Bible and chemistry or literature.
We don't know the difference; we just believe we must read it just like any other book.
Hallelujah.
The Bible and the Holy Spirit.
Read the Bible, read the Holy Spirit.
It means, the Bible itself is the letter inspired by the Spirit of God.
When you are reading the Bible, you are reading the Holy Spirit.
As the Lord breathed His Spirit into certain men, so He breathed His Spirit into certain books.
Holy men were carried along by the Spirit of God as they spoke the message that came from God.
Holy men were carried along by the Spirit.
It means, they were carried along by the Spirit - without the Spirit, they cannot...
They were carried along by the Spirit as they spoke the message that came from God.
God speaks to us through His Word, by His Spirit.
He walks to us by His Word, through His Spirit.
He calls you through His Word, by His Spirit.
He whispers to you through His Word, by His Spirit.
He greets you and you greet Him.
You speak to Him and He speaks to you through His Word, by His Spirit.
Holy men were carried along by the Spirit as they spoke the Word that came from God.
If you must read the Bible, you must be carried along by the Spirit.
If you must teach the Bible, you must be carried along by the Spirit.
If you must preach the Word of God, you must be carried along by the Spirit
because God's Word refreshes our mind and God's Spirit renews our strength.
If you must teach the Word, you must teach the Word by the Spirit.
If you must call the name, "Jesus!" - through His Word, by His Spirit.
"Be healed!" - through His Word, by His Spirit.
"Hallelujah!" - through His Word, by His Spirit.
"Hallelujah!" or whatever word in His presence
because God is Spirit and His worshippers must do so in Spirit and in truth.
Nowadays, we read the Bible, we pray and the Bible says we don't know how to pray
but the Spirit is helping our weakness.
We pray, we read without any regard of or attention to the Spirit of God.
We pray and read the Bible without any attention or regard for the Spirit of God.
We do not place Him where He rightly belongs,
knowing how important He is to us and God.
That is the Spirit of God.
We do not place the Spirit of God where He rightly belongs.
Your spirit needs to be free.
Free my spirit to follow You.
Please, don't forget that.
If your spirit is not free and you are hearing me, you only hear me to preach the Word,
to teach the Word but not to live it.
You cannot live by it because the spirit is not free.
Your spirit must act upon the Word to be part of the Word.
Free my spirit to follow You.
How can one be reading the Bible without seeking the attention of the Holy Spirit?
What are you reading?
You are not reading the Bible; you are reading history.
Reading history is reading about events -
what happened, in Jerusalem, Jeremiah, Jesus Christ.
The Holy Spirit is the most sensitive of beings
and is easily hurt by lack of attention and regard.
When you pick the Bible without seeking His attention, what are you reading?
Before reading the Bible, we need to seek the attention of the Holy Spirit
because the Bible is the tool in the hands of the Holy Spirit.
What is tool? - The Word of God.
Before reading the Bible, you need to seek the attention of who?
- The Holy Spirit.
Because the Bible itself, I mean, the Word of God itself is the tool in the hands of the Holy Spirit.
You cannot use it without the Holy Spirit.
It's a weapon and instrument in His hand.
The Holy Spirit is a Communicator.
When you open the Book of Romans 9:1, our conscience is the communication point.
The Holy Spirit is a Communicator and our heart is a contact point.
I mean, our heart is a communication point.
He cannot share with a heart full of bitterness.
He cannot share with a heart full of unforgiveness.
He cannot share with a heart full of hatred,
bad feelings towards others, your neighbour - the Holy Spirit cannot share with such a heart.
Can you see where your challenges and problems are coming from?
Tell your neighbour.
The Holy Spirit cannot share with a heart full of hatred, unforgiveness,
bitterness, envy, jealousy - the Holy Spirit cannot share with such a heart.
Can you see the reason why you cannot invite the Holy Spirit to your heart?
To all the hearts that are in bondage - be free!
Bondage of unforgiveness - be free!
Bondage of envy, jealousy - be free!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Without the freedom, liberty of your heart, you are just wasting your time;
you are calling the god you do not know.
Tell your neighbour.
If you hold grudges towards your neighbour,
you should not be surprised if the Bible has no meaning to you.
You can read your Bible hundred times.
As long as you hold grudges against anyone -
I mean bad feelings towards others, your neighbour - the Bible has no meaning to you.
Can you see the Bible you are carrying?
It is such a sensitive of being.
Such a sensitive of what? - Being.
Very sensitive.
Because it is the book of the Holy Spirit.
Reading the Bible, reading the Holy Spirit.
Easily hurt by lack of attention and regard.
Without the Bible, what else again? How will you talk to God? How will you have access to God?
Without the Bible...
It is our standard.
Let's ask ourselves a question.
Why does the Bible not come alive to some of us nowadays?
Can somebody answer the question?
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Because we don't know the importance of the Bible,
we always read the Bible with burdens, grudges, hatred.
Thank you.
Did you listen to that? Simple.
The Bible can no longer come alive because we read the Bible with so much unforgiveness,
envy and jealousy.
The Bible no longer comes alive because of the unforgiveness.
Tell your neighbour.
The Bible can no longer come alive because of the unforgiveness we hold,
bitterness, envy and jealousy.
We read with so much unforgiving spirit.
Where are we going from here?
Where there is no Bible, there is no Christianity.
Where there is no Bible, there is no believer.
Where there is no Bible, there is no born-again.
We are trapped now.
How do we get out of this captivity?
Advice.
Read the Bible as often as possible.
Tell your neighbour.
Keep meditating on it until it becomes reailty to you.
Meditating, meditating.
You may not get it at first when you read.
You may not understand it at first when you read.
That is why you have to continue to meditate on it until it becomes reality.
You may not get it the first time you read; keep meditating.
Read it slowly, attentively and repeatedly.
Your understanding of what you read may not be the understanding of the Holy Spirit.
You need the attention of the Holy Spirit.
That is why you read slowly, attentively and repeatedly.
Even though our reason may reject it, let our heart crave for it.
Do you know one thing?
Finally.
The Holy Spirit always rewards the obedient
but He does not necessarily reward good people, smart people like we are.
We are very good, smart in reading the Bible.
He does not necessarily reward good people, smart people, clever people, wealthy people;
He rewards obedient people.
The Holy Spirit always rewards the obedient.
He does not necessarily reward smart people, clever people, good people, wealthy people.
You know, we are very smart, very good, very clever, wealthy.
He does not necessarily reward them.
He rewards obedient people.
Trust and obey.
When we walk with the Lord
In the light of His Word
What a glory He sheds on our way
While we do His good will
He abides with us still
And with all who will trust and obey
Trust and obey
For there's no other way
To be happy in Jesus
But to trust and obey
Tell your neighbour.
The Holy Spirit always rewards the obedient.
I can't hear you.
He does not necessarily reward good people like you.
He does not necessarily reward smart people like you.
He does not necessarily reward a clever person like you.
He does not necessarily reward wealthy people like you.
He rewards obedient people.
Final advice.
The Holy Spirit always rewards the obedient.
He does not necessarily reward good people, brilliant people,
smart people, clever people, wealthy people.
Just talk - just name any adjective.
But He rewards obedient people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why fishermen were among his disciples.
Rustic people followed Him.
And you know what it took Paul to succeed - to become what he was.
So, when we are reading the Bible, put your knowledge aside.
There's a difference between supernatural and human natural gifts.
And we all know those things that follow human natural gifts -
talent, gift and education are under human natural gifts.
That is why people like me can be here.
If the reward was for the good, smart, clever, brilliant, I would not be in the position I am today.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour once again.
The Holy Spirit always rewards the obedient.
He does not necessarily reward good people, clever people, smart people,
brilliant people, wealthy people.
He rewards the obedient.
Trust and obey.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Don't forget your prayer.
Free me to follow You; I have decided!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You raise me up
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
When I am down and oh my soul so weary
When troubles come and my heart burdened be
When I am still and wait here in the silence
Until You come and stay awhile with me
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
You raise me up so I can stand on mountains
You raise me up to walk on stormy seas
I am strong when I am on your shoulders
You raise me up to more than I can be
Right now, whatever root of bitterness or unforgiveness that keeps unforgiveness alive -
be moved, in the name of Jesus!
That root that keeps unforgiveness alive - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
That root that keeps bitterness alive in you - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
That root that keeps envy, bitterness, sin alive - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
There is a root for all this.
There could be disagreement or whatever.
That root that keeps them alive - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
You keep saying, "No, no, I don't need to hold offence".
But before you know it, you hold offence.
There's a root.
It may be through help that someone is giving you.
It may be where you live.
That root that keeps them alive - be terminated, in the name of Jesus!
That root!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Overflow Congregation
In Jesus Christ's name we pray.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 07/07/2018
RV ROBERT BEGIER 08/07/2018